Let's cover the ITTOs of stakeholder
management.
So the ITTOs of identify stakeholders.
You're in the initiating process group.
We're trying to identify all potential
stakeholders.
Individuals, groups, departments,
organizations impacted by your project.
Out of them, we need to know who's going
to impact us.
So our inputs will have the project
charter.
It'll contain any high-level stakeholders.
stakeholders we already know about our
business documents that business case and
benefits management plans someone needed
something so those are stakeholders your
project management plan comes after we
move into planning obviously but our plans
especially stakeholder engagement and
communications are the who needs what when
where why how and then project documents
as we create them later might uncover new
stakeholders So remember,
this is going to be progressively
elaborated like every
other aspect of the project.
Agreements, contracts.
Stakeholders are definitely listed,
whoever's impacted.
And then you have those EFs and OPAs as
normal.
So we'll use expert judgment.
We'll gather data.
We'll cover a lot of these as we move into
the next slides.
Data analysis will do a stakeholder
analysis and document analysis.
We're trying to again
uncover all our stakeholders
and then figure out their interest impact.
And you'll see in a little bit,
we will create a stakeholder.
We'll also do data representation,
stakeholder mapping presentation,
and have meetings.
So we will see these coming up.
Your outputs, the oh so important
stakeholder register.
This will list all the stakeholders and
relevant information about them.
If after we're basic, the stakeholders
change because people will come and go
need that change request which will lead
to plan and document updates always know
that's a trio all right the ITTOs of plan
stakeholder engagement we're in planning
one of the first plans subsidiary plans
stakeholder engagement and communications
these are the who's needs what
when where why how how can we
approach appropriately engage
and involve the stakeholders.
Our inputs, the project charter again,
the project management plan.
We often will plan communications and
stakeholder engagement together.
We will end up having project documents
along the way.
And our agreements, again, list specific
stakeholders.
Tools and techniques will use expert
judgment again, data gathering,
benchmarking, comparing a previous
project, who the stakeholders are.
Data analysis, we'll do assumptions and
constraints analysis, a root cause
analysis to find out if on that previous
similar recently completed project,
we had missed someone, for example,
or not properly prioritize them.
We'll make decisions.
Yes, we'll actually prioritize
and rank the stakeholders
themselves, especially
if you have a lot of them.
And for data representation, so this is a
trio with those tools and techniques.
We'll gather the data.
We need some details.
We'll analyze the data, represent the
data, document it, create a diagram.
So you can use mind mapping and the
stakeholder engagement assessment matrix.
So we'll show you in the upcoming slides
how we create that and of course we're
having a planning meeting every time you
plan you always at least produce a plan
that will state what you're setting out to
accomplish how you'll do your processes in
this knowledge area manage stakeholder
engagement the ITTOs we are in executing
this is when we're doing the work of the
project so we'll manage stakeholders
expectations handle their issues build
trust that's the key in stakeholder
management is to build trust engage and
involve the stakeholders to support the
project best way to do that communicating
with them all right so our inputs our
project management plan
communications and stakeholder
engagement biggest pieces
and the change management plan.
Who's going to make changes?
Any stakeholder involved in the project.
So remember, we created that in the very
beginning, stating how
changes will be made.
Documents, we will have that change in
issue logs.
We will communicate
the dispositions of their
change requests and their
issues are being resolved.
Then you have those EFs and OPAs.
So tools and techniques, again,
we'll use expert judgment.
This is where we're involving,
engaging them in our meetings,
communicating with them.
So we'll use those communication skills
and get feedback.
We use those interpersonal team skills.
Again, manage conflict, use cultural and
political awareness.
We might have to negotiate with certain
stakeholders, observation and
conversation, just like when we are
communicating with them.
And this is where we will use the ground
rules.
Remember, acceptable behavior among the
stakeholders.
Again, we're in a global environment.
We have to set what are the expected ways
of communicating with everyone.
And, of course, we're having meetings.
So our outputs will be change requests.
So if someone is saying, as we're
communicating with them, engaging,
involving them, that they're not engaged
involved enough, getting as many
communications the right way they need
them.
That'll require a change request,
which leads to plan and document updates.
That's always a trio.
Last but not least, the ITTOs of monitor
stakeholder engagement.
So again, we're monitoring the
relationships.
That's the key for the stakeholder
management, knowledge area, building
relationships to engage them to support
our project.
So we're ensuring people are coming over
to our side to support the project.
Our inputs, your project management plan.
Always communications and stakeholder
engagement.
Who needs what, when, where, why,
how.
Project documents, we'll have that issue
log again, and the communications.
We always compare in every monitoring and
controlling process, the plan,
what was agreed upon to the data,
what is actually.
happening actuals and those EEFs and OPAs.
So we'll do data analysis.
So again, this is where we're checking.
I'm going right down here to data
representation.
We'll be looking at our stakeholder
engagement assessment matrix to see if the
current and desired engagement levels are
working.
We're getting our stakeholders over to
support our project or lead.
Get others to support the project.
All right, we'll make decisions.
If we have to change our approach, all
right, we'll make
decisions including voting.
We use our communication skills.
It's imperative we get feedback and ask
the questions.
Are you getting what you need when you
need them?
And if they're saying
no, or they still don't
support the project,
it's your job to try to do.
get them on our side,
show them the benefits
of the project, how it will benefit them.
Of course, we'll use those interpersonal
and team skills, those soft skills,
active listening, cultural and political
awareness again, leadership skills,
imparting vision and networking.
These are all similar to our communication
processes.
And of course, we'll have meetings.
So your plan and data, always come in to
our.
monitoring and controlling processes.
What goes out?
Information, the progress with stakeholder
engagement.
If we're not progressing as planned,
change requests.
We'll update, if approved,
we'll update any plans,
especially communications
and stakeholder engagement.
We have to change our
approach, strategy to get those
stakeholders over on our
side to support the project.
That's what we're doing.
through the change request.
We'll update the plans and documents
accordingly.